(503) 272-1842 brian.ryer@me.com 5812 SE Center Street, Portland, OR 97206

Profile

I am a technical writer, editor, content manager and information designer with well developed skills in project management, web development, business analysis, presentation and research. I am fluent in German and held a TS/SCI security clearance.

Experience

TECHNICAL WRITER & CONTENT DEVELOPER, SMARSH; PORTLAND, OR – 10/2016-08/2018 Wrote, edited, and managed customer facing and internal documentation in collaboration with Product Managers and SMEs; built lightweight content management tools and administered multiple content management systems (SharePoint, Salesforce, Confluence, WalkMe, Snaglt).

TECHNICAL WRITER, HEWLETT PACKARD; VANCOUVER, WA - 10/2014-09/2016

Researched, wrote, and edited technical documentation; recorded and edited training videos and related materials; built lightweight product information tools and administered multiple content management systems for R&D Lab of Fortune 500 technology company as contractor.

TECHNICAL WRITER, COLLEGENET: PORTLAND, OR – 11/2009-8/2013

Wrote and edited documentation for multiple web applications with FrameMaker; wrote responses to RFP's for multiple products with MS Word and Adobe Acrobat; managed projects for front-end redesign of client forms; designed, built, tested and maintained web forms using XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript and proprietary languages.

FREELANCE DEVELOPER, VARIOUS SMALL BUSINESSES; PORTLAND, OR - 6/2007-11/2009 & 9/2013-10/2014 Designed, built and maintained equity tracking database and reporting tools in MS Excel for Lattice Capital Management; managed project to build and populated CMS using XML, Python and Adobe InDesign for website and internal production of materials for LitART LLC; designed and built various websites with HTML, XML, CSS and Javascript; trained users to maintain websites.

PUBLISHING SPECIALIST, CONTENT MANAGEMENT ASSOCIATES; OREGON CITY, OR - 6/2005-6/2007 Managed multiple publishing projects and associated client accounts; analyzed, designed and built SQL and XML document structures; wrote and edited in-house documentation.

DATA RESOURCE GROUP ADMINISTRATOR, GOLDMAN SACHS; FRANKFURT, GERMANY - 6/1995-6/2003 Analyzed and distributed financial data and news with multiple products; acted as web master for Information Services Group intranet; managed content library with multiple sources; led and coordinated 10 member presentation team; designed and built presentations with MS PowerPoint for internal and external clients; designed and built time sheet application in MS Excel; designed and built conference communications databases in MS Access.

Education

University of Maryland, Frankfurt, Germany - Linguistics (non degree, AA equivalent), 1988 University of the Pacific, Stockton, CA - General (non degree), 1981 School for the Creative and Performing Arts, Chula Vista, CA - High School Diploma, 1980

CERTIFICATION

Goethe Institute, Frankfurt, Germany - Mittelstufenprüfung Zertifikat (university proficiency), 1989 Doing Journalism with Data, Portland, OR - European Journalism Centre, 2014

Service

Radio Telecommunications Specialist, 533rd MI Battalion; Frankfurt, Germany 1984-1992

Skills

Technical Writing: Ulysses, MS Word, oXygen, FrameMaker, Adobe Acrobat, Markdown Content Management: Confluence, SharePoint, Wordpress, GIT, CVS, Subversion, wiki variants Project Management: GTD, Jira, Asana, Slack, BaseCamp, MS Project, Agile and variants Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, XML/XSLT/XQuery

Online

Website: bkryer.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/bkryer